# Thomas J Lazore

# Software Developer

Address Savannah, United States, 31410

**Phone** 315-778-6632

E-mail tomlazore@gmail.com

Software developer currently attending Georgia Tech's Full Stack Coding Boot Camp. Working with technologies such as JavaScript, Express, and Node for development of group and solo projects. Past relevant experience interning as a research assistant while developing the front end of a project for Rochester Institute of Technology. A leadership background as a paramedic has developed skills to be an effective and resourceful team member as well as independent worker.

# **Projects**

#### **Never Alone**

github.com/tlaze/NeverAlone | never-alone-platform.herokuapp.com/

- **Description:** Team of 4 members developing a social media application geared towards mental health. User's can post their thoughts and how they feel. While signing up users are greeted with a welcome email thanking them and informing them of the apps mission statement.
- **Responsibilities:** Creation, editing, and deletion of posts | Making the application mobile responsive.
- Technology Used:

HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Javascript | Node | Express | Handlebars | Express-Session | MySQL2 | Sequelize | Connect-Session-Sequelize | Heroku | Nodemailer

#### Tech Blog

github.com/tlaze/tech-blog | cryptic-thicket-49114.herokuapp.com/

- **Description:** Forum based application for creating posts and adding comments. The homepage displays all the posts and comments users have made. Logged in users can view their dashboard containing all the posts they created. They also have the option to create, update, or delete their posts. After being inactive for a while users are logged out.
- Technology Used:

HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Javascript | Node | Express | Handlebars | Express-Session | MySQL2 | Sequelize | Connect-Session-Sequelize | Heroku

#### **Weather Dashboard**

github.com/tlaze /weather-dashboard | tlaze.github.io /weather-dashboard/

- Description: Fetches data from a third party API to display current and future
  weather conditions for cities that users enter. Previous searches are saved even
  after users refresh or leave the page.
- Technology Used:

HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Javascript | JQuery | OpenWeatherOneAPI

#### **Education**

2021-09 - 20212

### **Full Stack Coding Boot Camp**

Georgia Institute of Technology - Atlanta, GA

2018-09 - 2019-09

## **Computer Science**

Monroe Community College - Rochester, NY

- Relevant Coursework Completed: Intro to Computer Science with Java & Programming with Python
- Completed a summer internship with Rochester Institute of Technology working on the front-end development of an application that recognizes handwritten mathematical formulas and converts it into searchable queries.

# **Work History**

2017-09 - 2020-03

#### **Paramedic**

Irondequoit Ambulance, Irondequoit, NY

- Triaged injuries by communicating with patients, bystanders and family members, and identified appropriate medical facility for transport.
- Used EMSCharts to accurately document services provided to reduce liability and improve patient care.
- Trained EMTs in basic life support skills, oxygen therapy, and wound care.
- Communicated with hospital personnel and dispatchers to provide information about situation, arrange reception of victims and receive instructions for further treatment.

2019-05 - 2019-08

#### Research Assistant Intern

Rochester Institute Of Technology, Rochester, NY

- Prepared materials for submission to agencies and foundations to fund research.
- Researched and interpreted large volumes of scientific data and literature about search interfaces and indexing mathematical formulas.
- Used Zotero to prepare articles, reports and presentations.
- Presented technical research results to diverse audiences through written, visual and oral media.